SHAIBU ALI JUMA

PROFILE SUMMARY

A passionate electrical and electronic engineer who is able to provide excellent problem-solving skills using creative, innovative and strong interpersonal skills. My interests lie in electrical & electronics systems, renewable energy and IOT. I excel at lecturing & training, research, data analysis and identifying problems and offering possible solutions.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 06 October 1990

Sex: Male
Nationality: Malawian

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering,

[2018]

Pan African University Institute of Basic Science, Technology and Innovation – Kenya

Major: Power Systems

Research Area: Distribution System Network Reconfiguration

Bachelor of Engineering (HONS), Electrical and Electronic Engineering
 University of East London in collaboration with Linton College University – Malaysia

[2014]

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

- Planning, Design, Installation and Management of Renewable Energy Systems: Test and Training
 Centre for Renewable Energy Technologies (TCRET), Mzuzu University [2021]
- Siemens Mechatronics Systems program: Dedan Kimathi University of Technology- Kenya [2019]
- Executive Diploma in Project Management: CADD Centre Malaysia [2013]

WORK HISTORY

LECTURER; MZUZU UNIVERSITY - MZUZU, MALAWI

[April 2021 – Present]

TUTORIAL FELLOW; DEDAN KIMATHI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY – NYERI, KENYA [May 2019 – Mar 2021]

JUNIOR SUPERVISOR; Sharma Electrical Contractor – Blantyre, MALAWI [Jan – Nov 2016]

KEY PROJECTS

Completed Research Projects/Activities

- M.Sc. Research Project (Period of study 2016-1018)
 Optimal Radial Distribution Network Reconfiguration Using Modified Shark Smell Optimization. <u>Supervisors</u>: Prof. Christopher Maina Muriithi and Prof. Livingstone M. Ngoo
- 2. **B.Eng. Research Project** (Period of study Jan-Dec 2013). Tele-operated Camera. <u>Supervisor:</u> Mr. Ery Rizaldy

Current Research Projects/Activities

- 1. **B.Sc. Research Project** (Period of study 2021-Current)
 - Power Theft Monitoring System.
- 2. **Mzuni Energy Club Project** (Period of study 2021-Current) Gas Leakage Detector System.

AWARDS, ACHIEVEMENTS AND LEADERSHIP ROLES

- 1. 2022: TOP 15 TOTALENERGIES STARTUPPER MALAWI
- 2. 2016: Pan African University MSc. Scholarship Award (PAUSTI-Kenya)
- 2011-2012: Dean's List Certificates (Linton Kolej University- Malaysia)
- 4. 2009: National Schools Science Fair (4th prize) (Kalibu Academy-Malawi)
- 5. 2009: Best AS Level Mathematics and Physics Student (Kalibu Academy Malawi)
- 6. 2009: Hockey Captain (Kalibu Academy- Malawi)
- 7. 2006: Basketball and Hockey Captain (Watershed College-Zimbabwe)

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Graduate Engineer– Board of Engineers of Malawi Graduate Engineer – Malawi Engineering Institute

DORIS CHUNGA

PROFILE SUMMARY

A result-oriented final year engineering student with passion for renewable energy technologies.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Age: 25 years old Sex: Female Nationality: Malawian

EDUCATION

Bachelor of science in Renewable Energy Technologies

[2018-Current]

Mzuzu University – Malawi

KEY PROJECTS

Current Research Projects/Activities

1. **Mzuni Energy Club Project** (Period of Oct 2021-Current) Gas Leakage Detector System.

AWARDS, ACHIEVEMENTS AND LEADERSHIP ROLES

- 1. 2022: TOP 15 TOTALENERGIES STARTUPPER MALAWI
- 2. 2022: Student Representative
- 3. 2021: Co-Founder of Mzuni Energy Innovation Club **(MZUNI-Malawi)** Club Coordinator
- 4. Marketing and social media manager

DEREK MANJAWIRA

PROFILE SUMMARY

A self-motivated, energetic, diligent and result oriented professional who can provide innovative technical skills in electrical and electronics engineering as well as renewable energy technologies.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 17 May 1996

Sex: Male
Nationality: Malawian

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of science in Renewable Energy Technologies

[2019-Current]

Mzuzu University – Malawi

• Diploma in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

[2018]

MUBAS -Polytechnic – Malawi

Project- Design and Implementation of a Smart Security System

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

NPTEL ONLINE CERTIFICATE: Fuzzy Logic Systems

[2019]

•

WORK HISTORY

ELECTRICAL SUPERVISOR; MAPHIRI ELECTRICAL CONTRACTOR

ELECTRICAL INTERN; BLANTYRE WATER BOARD

[Jan 2019 – Present] [July 2017 – Dec 2017]

KEY PROJECTS

Current Research Projects/Activities

Mzuni Energy Club Project (Period of Oct 2021-Current)
 Gas Leakage Detector System.

AWARDS, ACHIEVEMENTS AND LEADERSHIP ROLES

- 1. 2022: TOP 15 TOTALENERGIES STARTUPPER MALAWI
- 2. 2021: Co-Founder of Mzuni Energy Innovation Club (MZUNI-Malawi)
- 3. Events Coordinator

MATTHEWS MCHENULA

PROFILE SUMMARY

Well versed in electronics designing and programming skills. Have sound knowledge in electrical and electronic engineering and IOT systems. Able to work under minimum supervision, with good time management skills and sound judgement.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 03 March 1993

Sex: Male
Nationality: Malawian

EDUCATION

Bachelor of science in Renewable Energy Technologies

[2019-Current]

Mzuzu University – Malawi

• Diploma in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

[2018]

MUBAS -Polytechnic – Malawi

Project-Laser Beam Detection System

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

ANTHENA GLOBAL EDUCATION: ARDUINO PROGRAMMING AND DESIGN

[2022]

WORK HISTORY

TECHNICIAN TRAINEE; ESCOM
ELECTRICAL INTERN; RAPID COMMUNICATION LIMITED

[Feb 2021 – Dec 2021]

[April 2020 - Sept 2020]

KEY PROJECTS

Current Research Projects/Activities

1. Mzuni Energy Club Project (Period of Oct 2021-Current)

Gas Leakage Detector System. (TOP 15 TOTALENERGIES STARTUPPER MALAWI)

2. Communication App (2021)

An android communication app between patients and doctors for booking appointments and prescription check-in.

3. Medical detection device (2020)

Detection of intrapartum fever in pregnant women to reduce maternal and neonatal deaths.

AWARDS, ACHIEVEMENTS AND LEADERSHIP ROLES

- 1. 2022: TOP 15 TOTALENERGIES STARTUPPER MALAWI
- 2. 2022: Student President of Malawi Engineering Institution (MZUNI-Chapter)
- 3. 2022: Student Representative
- 4. 2021: Co-Founder of Mzuni Energy Innovation Club (MZUNI-Malawi)
- 5. 3rd position Malawi innovators and design competition. (Polytechnic Design Studio)
- 6. 2nd position: Arduino day competition